

Shivam Goyal

Data Science | Machine Learning | Deep Learning Enthusiast

I'm a budding Data Scientist who tries to get insights about what's benificial for a business and what's not by simply applying machine learning & statistical analysis on the pre-analysis data. I do love to keep the design and development process closer together, creating experiences designed for users first, while also taking care of business and brand needs.

shivamgoyal1899@gmail.com

(+91) 90122 18994

shivamgoyal.tk

in linkedin.com/in/ShivamGoyal1899

EDUCATION

B.E. Computer Engineering

Thapar Institute of Engineering & Technology

2018 - Present

8.63 CGPA

Senior Secondary

Divine Educational Institute

2017

93.80 %

PROJECTS

Gesture Controlled Robotic Arm

- This project focuses on replicating your hand movements to the robotic arm through deep learning model and openCV. So, no extra sensors are required except a laptop with a working webcam.

CreditCard Fraud Detection System 🗗

A Credit Card Fraud Detection System based on Machine Learning algorithms. It sorts out fraudulent transactions from genuine transactions.

Movie Recommendation Engine

It's a Movie Recommender System that predicts which movies you should watch next on the basis of your liked/last watched movie.

Affekt [Emotion Recognition App]

Using Microsoft's Emotion API, Affekt can detect the emotion of the people in an image or even in real time!

WORK EXPERIENCE

Machine Learning Internship

Youstart Labs

06/2019 - Present

Bengaluru

- Developed Android Apps based on Ml Algorithms.
- Conducted Bootcamps on Python & Git.
- Launched a brand new free MOOCs website focusing on Artificial Intelligence & Machine Learning Projects.

Contact: Abhishek Rathore - linkedin/abhishek87

Digital Marketing Internship

Inkpothub

Patiala 02/2019 - Present

Contact: Rishabh Sahani - fb/rishabh.sahni.3956

Android TV [ADT-2] Development Team Google Developers

Contact: Loic Wei Yu Neng – loicweiyuneng@google.com

SKILLS

Web Development Python **Data Structures JavaScript** C / C++

ACHIEVEMENTS

picoCTF (2018)

Bagged Global Rank 1415 in picoCTF 2018 with a score of 6435 among 16143 teams worldwide.

Google HashCode (2019)

Bagged Global Rank 945 & All India Rank 33 in Google HashCode Online Qualification Round 2019 with a score of 680469 among 6671 teams worldwide.

ORGANIZATIONS

ORION'19 - InterYear TechFest TIET

WebMaster, App Developer & Tech Team Member

IEI Thapar Students' Chapter

WebMaster & Tech Team Member

MaRS TIET

WebMaster & Tech Team Member

Facebook Developer Circle

Institute Lead

MAJOR CERTIFICATES

Mathematics for Machine Learning Specialization Imperial College London

Applied Data Science with Python Specialization University of Michigan

Machine Learning

Stanford University

LANGUAGES

English Full Professional Proficiency German

Limited Working Proficiency

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Limited Working Proficiency

INTERESTS

Blogging Solo Travelling LAN Gaming

Event Management

Graphic Designing